Dmitrii Kuvaiskii

Noethnitzer strasse 25
O1187 Dresden

Mobile: +49 (176) 9978 5337

Email: dmitrii kuvaiskii

Germany

Email: dmitrii.kuvaiskii@gmail.com
Homepage: https://dimakuv.github.io/
GitHub: https://github.com/dimakuv

Research Interests

My research interests lie in the field of dependability in software systems, with a particular focus on fault tolerance and security. Within these fields, I investigate the applicability of modern hardware extensions to increase reliability of real-world applications while imposing low overheads.

Education

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science (Dec 2013 - present)

TU Dresden, Germany

Advisors: Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer and Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia

Master of Science in Computer Science (Oct 2011 - Nov 2013)

TU Dresden, Germany

Diplom in Electrical Engineering (Sep 2004 - Jul 2010)

Bauman University, Moscow, Russia

Employment

Auriga Inc, Moscow, Russia, Sep 2010 - Aug 2011

Certification engineer, Software developer

Responsibilities:

- documenting and testing code of the PikeOS embedded operating system (C);
- writing medical special-purpose programs (C++ and C#).

Diasoft, Moscow, Russia, Sep 2007 - Aug 2010

Software developer

Responsibilities: programming insurance subsystems using Transact SQL and Delphi.

Honors and Awards

Carter Award (best student paper) at DSN'15

Best paper award at SRDS'14

Erasmus Mundus Action 2 MULTIC scholarship, 2011-2013

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii

Ph.D. Dissertation

Topic: Dependable Systems Leveraging new ISA extensions (preliminary) **Supervisors:** Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer and Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia

In the context of my Ph.D. dissertation, I investigate and build systems to increase software dependability leveraging recent sets of extensions in Intel processors, with the focus on software-based fault tolerance and security for legacy C/C++ programs.

Research projects:

Detailed evaluation of Intel MPX and discussion of its applicability in comparison to other bounds-checking approaches [USENIX ATC'17]*;

SGXBounds: LLVM-based bounds checker to detect and tolerate security bugs in multithreaded legacy C/C++ programs inside Intel SGX enclaves [EuroSys'17]*;

Elzar: LLVM compiler pass to detect and mask transient CPU faults in multithreaded legacy C/C++ programs using Intel AVX [**DSN'16**] [code];

HAFT: LLVM compiler pass to detect and tolerate transient CPU faults in multithreaded legacy C/C++ programs using Intel TSX [EuroSys'16] [code];

Δ-*Encoding*: Source-to-source compiler to detect transient and permanent CPU faults in legacy C programs utilizing unused IPC resources of modern CPUs [DSN'15].

Publications

Conference publications:

Intel MPX Explained

Oleksii Oleksenko, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer

USENIX ATC 2017. (Under submission)

SGXBounds: Memory Safety for Shielded Execution

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Oleksii Oleksenko, Sergei Arnautov, Bohdan Trach, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and

Christof Fetzer

EuroSys 2017. (Under submission)

Elzar: Triple Modular Redundancy using Intel Advanced Vector Extensions

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Oleksii Oleksenko, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer

DSN 2016.

Software artifact: https://github.com/tudinfse/elzar

HAFT: Hardware-Assisted Fault Tolerance

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Rasha Faqeh, Pramod Bhatotia, Pascal Felber, and Christof Fetzer

EuroSys 2016.

Software artifact: https://github.com/tudinfse/haft

Δ-Encoding: Practical Encoded Processing

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii and Christof Fetzer

DSN 2015. Carter Award (best student paper).

HardPaxos: Replication hardened against hardware errors

Diogo Behrens, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, and Christof Fetzer

SRDS 2014. Best paper award.

Dmitrii Kuvaiskii

Extended Abstracts:

Efficient Fault Tolerance using Intel MPX and TSX Oleksii Oleksenko, Dmitrii Kuvaiskii, Pramod Bhatotia, Christof Fetzer, and Pascal Felber Fast abstract at **DSN 2016**.

Talks

ACM EuroSys'16, London, April 2016 HAFT: Hardware-Assisted Fault Tolerance

IEEE DSN'16, Toulouse, June 2016

Elzar: Triple Modular Redundancy using Intel Advanced Vector Extensions

IEEE DSN'15, Rio de Janeiro, June 2015 Δ -Encoding: Practical Encoded Processing

Teaching experience

Teaching assistant: Distributed Systems Engineering courses, TU Dresden, Dec 2013 - present.

- Concurrent and Distributed Systems lab, Summer Semesters 2014 2016
- Principles of Dependable Systems exercises, Winter Semesters 2014 2016
- Software Fault Tolerance exercises, Summer Semesters 2014 2016

Professional activities

Shadow PC member: EuroSys 2016.

Skills

Languages: C, C++, Assembly (expert), Unix shell, Python, R, (competent);

Frameworks: LLVM, gdb, Intel Pin, Intel SDE;

Technologies: Intel SSE/AVX, Intel TSX, Intel MPX, Intel SGX.

References

Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer

TU Dresden, Germany

Email: christof.fetzer@tu-dresden.de

Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia

University of Edinburgh, UK

Email: pramod.bhatotia@gmail.com

Prof. Dr. Pascal Felber

University of Neuchatel

Email: pascal.felber@unine.ch